<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ComputerStarter</string>
    <!--Brief Titles-->
    <string name="brief_description_gpu">
        Brief Description of a GPU
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_cpu">
        Brief Description of a CPU
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mot">
        Brief Description of a Motherboard
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mem">
        Brief Description of Memory
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_stor">
        Brief Description of a Storage Unit
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_psu">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_cpucool">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_case">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_os">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mon">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_per">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>

    <!--Ports Titles-->
    <string name="ports_gpu">
        Ports of a GPU
    </string>
    <string name="ports_cpu">
        Cores and More
    </string>
    <string name="ports_mot">
        Ports of a Motherboard
    </string>
    <string name="ports_mem">
        Ports of a Memory
    </string>
    <string name="ports_stor">
        Ports of a Storage
    </string>
    <string name="ports_psu">
        Ports of a Power Supply Unit
    </string>

    <!--Component Descriptions-->
    <string name="gpu_desc">
        Storage is a very important component of the PC just like everything else in the PC.
        The storage component is a piece of hardware that has the capability to hold information
        within a certain time frame or forever.In other words, it is a place to store your data
        either temporarily or permanently.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_desc">
        The CPU (central processing unit) is often called the brain of the system because it handles
        instructions from both hardware and software. The CPU lives on on the motherboard in the CPU
        socket covered by a heat sink. The CPU at its most basic performs calculations from instructions
        it’s sent from peripheral devices or inner hardware like the RAM. Today you will see many options
        for CPUs from different manufacturers with different line ups of product. Each CPU has its own
        amount of cores and architectures that differentiates it from other manufacturers or even from
        older generations of the same product. From experience, do not cheap out on this part of the
        computer because no expensive GPU or amount of RAM will stop the bottleneck that will occur
        because of an older low core CPU.
    </string>
    <string name="mot_desc">
        The motherboard acts as the foundation for all other computer parts to live on. It serves to
        route power to help coordinate how the components work together. It is not the same as the CPU
        since it does not make computations. The motherboard does more organization of the computation
        and results. It does not affect performance, but the sockets available will since an older CPU
        socket will only support older CPUs and more sockets for more RAM would increase the performance
        of the computer. The motherboard is also home to the BIOS(Basic Input/Output System) which allows
        you to view hardware information, change your boot drive, manage power settings, and overclock and
        underclock the CPU or RAM.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_desc">
        The memory or more commonly known as RAM (random access memory) is a short term memory location for
        the computer. Without RAM the computer would take much longer to open applications or do tasks. It
        is able to retrieve and store data the computer needs now or soon at high speeds. Unlike the actual
        storage of the computer, it only stores data when the computer is powered. The high speeds allow the
        CPU to do more computations without having to dig through a slower regular storage drive. RAM is
        usually bought in quantities of gigabytes(GB) in increments of 8 GBs in single stick or multiple
        all the way up to 128 GBs of RAM.
    </string>
    <string name="stor_desc">
        Storage is a very important component of the PC just like everything else in the PC. The storage component
        is a piece of hardware that has the capability to hold information within a certain time frame or forever.
        In other words, it is a place to store your data either temporarily or permanently.
    </string>
    <string name="psu_desc">
        Gives power to all the components in the PC.
    </string>

    <!--Ports Description-->
    <string name="gpu_ports_description">
        Depending on the GPU you purchase and when you purchased it the ports on the GPU may differ
        a little, but not by too much. For example, if you were to purchase a GPU back in 2003 the
        ports that would be included with it would consist of the DVI port, a VGA port and a S-Video
        port. If you were to purchase the up and coming GPU in the market you would find yourself having
        many HDMI ports, some DisplayPorts and depending on the GPU manufacturer you could find yourself
        having a DVI or even a VGA port.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_ports_description">
        The main two companies producing CPUs are AMD and Intel. The core count can go from two all the
        way up to sixty-four for professional settings. Clock speed is another piece of information that
        is advertised a lot when shopping for CPUs. Clock speed is measured in megahertz(MHz) or gigahertz
        (GHz) and means how many instructions a CPU can handle per second. The speed of the computer will
        depend on multiple factors other than the clock speed like the other components.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_ports_description">
    </string>
    <string name="stor_ports_description">
    </string>
    <string name="mot_ports_description">
        The back panel of the motherboard holds many of the ports needed to attach peripherals to interact
        with the computer. Most newer boards contain a HDMI or Displayport for the monitor, usb ports for
        mouse and keyboard or any more accessories, and many I/O connectors.
    </string>
    <string name="psu_ports_description">
        Connection for the power cord to the computer, the fan that pulls out the heat from the internal
        of the PSU, a switch to change the voltage provided and a rocker switch to turn the power supply
        on and off.
    </string>

    <string-array name="comp_names">
        <item>CPU</item>
        <item>MotherBoard</item>
        <item>Memory</item>
        <item>Storage</item>
        <item>Video Card</item>
        <item>Power Supply</item>
        <item>Raspberry Pi and More</item>
        <item>Arduino and More</item>
        <item>CPU Cooler</item>
        <item>Case</item>
        <item>OS</item>
        <item>Monitor</item>
        <item>Peripherals</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_login">LoginActivity</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome !"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_login">real_login</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_register">real_register</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_profile">real_profile</string>
    <string name="title_activity_education_tabbed">Education_Tabbed</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Beginner</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Moderate</string>
    <string name="tab_text_3">Expert</string>

    <string name="link_title">Links to Further your knowledge</string>
    <string name="cpu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mot_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/m/mothboar.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/m/mothboar.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mem_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/r/ram.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/r/ram.htm</a></string>
    <string name="stor_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/s/stordevi.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/s/stordevi.htm</a></string>
    <string name="gpu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/v/video-card.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/v/video-card.htm</a></string>
    <string name="psu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/p/power-supply.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/p/power-supply.htm</a></string>
    <string name="button">Button</string>
    <!--
    <string name="rasp_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="ard_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="cool_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="case_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="os_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mon_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="per_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    -->
    <string name="pref_previously_started">false</string>
</resources>