<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ComputerStarter</string>
    <!--Brief Titles-->
    <string name="brief_description_gpu">
        Brief Description of a GPU
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_cpu">
        Brief Description of a CPU
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mot">
        Brief Description of a Motherboard
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mem">
        Brief Description of Memory
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_stor">
        Brief Description of a Storage Unit
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_psu">
        Brief Description of a Power Supply
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_cpucool">
        Brief Description of the CPU cooler
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_case">
        Brief Description of the Case
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_os">
        Brief Description of the Operating System
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_mon">
        Brief Description of the Monitor
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_per">
        Brief Description of the Peripherals
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_rasp">
        Brief Description of a Raspberry Pi
    </string>
    <string name="rasp_example">
        Raspberry Pi Humidity Sensor using the DHT22 step by step
    </string>
    <string name="brief_description_ard">
        Brief Description of a Arduino
    </string>

    <!--Ports Titles-->
    <string name="ports_gpu">
        Ports of a GPU
    </string>
    <string name="ports_cpu">
        Cores and More
    </string>
    <string name="ports_mot">
        Ports of a Motherboard
    </string>
    <string name="ports_mem">
        Ports of a Memory
    </string>
    <string name="ports_stor">
        Types of Storage Devices
    </string>
    <string name="ports_psu">
        Ports of a Power Supply Unit
    </string>
    <string name="ports_cpucool">
        Types of Coolers
    </string>
    <string name="ports_case">
        Types of Cases
    </string>
    <string name="ports_os">
        Types of Operating Systems
    </string>
    <string name="ports_mon">
        Monitor Features
    </string>
    <string name="ports_per">
        Examples of Peripherals
    </string>

    <!--Basic Component Descriptions-->
    <string name="gpu_desc_basic">
        The GPU or the video card is one component most associated with gamers. It is an optional
        expansion to the computer used most commonly to run video games. Some CPUs have integrated
        graphics that allow them to be used like a GPU with limitations.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_desc_basic">
        The CPU is the core of any computer as it handles instructions and executes them while interacting
        with both hardware and software.
    </string>
    <string name="mot_desc_basic">
        The motherboard is where all the components live on top of. Every part of the computer will connect
        to it someway and will coordinate with them.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_desc_basic">
        The memory or RAM is the short term memory of the computer. It allows the computer to do tasks
        at higher speeds and can be as small as 8 GBs to 128 GBs.
    </string>
    <string name="stor_desc_basic">
        The storage is the component that holds all your personal data and anything else the computer
        stores long term.
    </string>
    <string name="psu_desc_basic">
        The power supply is what powers the entire system.
    </string>
    <string name="cpucool_desc_basic">
        The CPU cooler makes sure the CPU is running at a safe cool temperature.
    </string>
    <string name="case_desc_basic">
        The case houses the computer’s components.
    </string>
    <string name="os_desc_basic">
        An operating system is a necessary piece of software that allows you to interface with a computer.
    </string>
    <string name="mon_desc_basic">
        The monitor allows you to view what is happening on your computer.
    </string>
    <string name="per_desc_basic">
        The peripherals are the accessories that you can plug into the computer. They add functionality
        to a computer.
    </string>

    <!--Basic Ports Description-->
    <string name="gpu_ports_description_basic">
        Newer GPUs usually come with a variety of ports for monitors like HDMI or display ports or even
        DVI or VGA ports.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_ports_description_basic">
        The two choices you will have are AMD and Intel.More cores and a higher clock speed (GHz or MHz)
        will help your system run better.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_ports_description_basic">
    </string>
    <string name="stor_ports_description_basic">
        Ram is a short term storage different from the storage discussed here. Storage usually comes down
        to either HDD(Hard Drive Disk) or SSD(Solid State Drive).
    </string>
    <string name="mot_ports_description_basic">
        The board has many ports and sockets for each part to attach to. The CPU socket needs attention
        because it will decide the type of CPU you can get. The ports exposed to the outside will be for
        the many accessories like keyboards, mice, and more
    </string>
    <string name="psu_ports_description_basic">
        The power supply comes with plugs for all components to maintain their power. It has a power
        switch accessible from the outside to turn it on or off.
    </string>
    <string name="cpucool_ports_description_basic">
        The options for cooling are heat sinks with fan or liquid cooling. The first uses a dab of
        thermal paste to cool the CPU. Liquid cooling is more complicated and expensive to safely use
        liquid to cool components more efficiently.
    </string>
    <string name="case_ports_description_basic">
        Full Tower is the large case.
	    Mid Tower is the medium size of the case.
	    Micro-ATX is the small.
	    Mini-ITX is the smallest size.
        Check with each part to make sure that they are compatible with whichever you choose.

    </string>
    <string name="os_ports_description_basic">
        Windows is the most widely used operating system and will work with most software.MacOS is only
        available for Apple laptops and will have specific software that is able to run on it. It is possible
        to run on other machines, but it will take some work.Linux is a free and open source operating system.
        It’s not very beginner friendly, but it is the most customizable operating system with many branches of
        it with specific uses in mind.

    </string>
    <string name="mon_ports_description_basic">
        Size is just how big the screen is.Resolution is the number of pixels on the monitor which can affect the
        image quality. Refresh rate matters mostly to only gamers because it involves fast movements and how often
        the screen refreshes with new information.
    </string>
    <string name="per_ports_description_basic">
        Mouse and keyboard are the most common and help to navigate a computer.Speakers are also common since
        most monitors do not come with speakers built in. Printers are the last example and help export
        documents to the real world.

    </string>

    <!--Component Descriptions-->
    <string name="gpu_desc">
        Storage is a very important component of the PC just like everything else in the PC.
        The storage component is a piece of hardware that has the capability to hold information
        within a certain time frame or forever.In other words, it is a place to store your data
        either temporarily or permanently.
    </string>
    <string name="ard_desc">
        Arduino is an open source platform which is designed to be easy to use. The Arduino boards
        can read inputs and turn them into outputs making it a good microcontroller. The Arduino
        requires a separate computer in order to use the Arduino software, but that software is
        available on all three major operating systems. The Arduino language is designed to be
        accessible and the board itself is cheap making it a beginner friendly way to experiment
        with electronic projects.
    </string>
    <string name="rasp_desc">
        A raspberry pi is a low price, credit card sized computer that can do most of anything that
        a full sized computer can do. Once a keyboard, mouse, and screen are plugged in then it can
        be used like a regular computer. It’s small size allows it to be used in projects that
        require a brain to direct commands. It can connect to the internet and can be used to teach
        many things such as how to program in Python to building smart mirrors.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_desc">
        The CPU (central processing unit) is often called the brain of the system because it handles
        instructions from both hardware and software. The CPU lives on on the motherboard in the CPU
        socket covered by a heat sink. The CPU at its most basic performs calculations from instructions
        it’s sent from peripheral devices or inner hardware like the RAM. Today you will see many options
        for CPUs from different manufacturers with different line ups of product. Each CPU has its own
        amount of cores and architectures that differentiates it from other manufacturers or even from
        older generations of the same product. From experience, do not cheap out on this part of the
        computer because no expensive GPU or amount of RAM will stop the bottleneck that will occur
        because of an older low core CPU.
    </string>
    <string name="mot_desc">
        The motherboard acts as the foundation for all other computer parts to live on. It serves to
        route power to help coordinate how the components work together. It is not the same as the CPU
        since it does not make computations. The motherboard does more organization of the computation
        and results. It does not affect performance, but the sockets available will since an older CPU
        socket will only support older CPUs and more sockets for more RAM would increase the performance
        of the computer. The motherboard is also home to the BIOS(Basic Input/Output System) which allows
        you to view hardware information, change your boot drive, manage power settings, and overclock and
        underclock the CPU or RAM.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_desc">
        The memory or more commonly known as RAM (random access memory) is a short term memory location for
        the computer. Without RAM the computer would take much longer to open applications or do tasks. It
        is able to retrieve and store data the computer needs now or soon at high speeds. Unlike the actual
        storage of the computer, it only stores data when the computer is powered. The high speeds allow the
        CPU to do more computations without having to dig through a slower regular storage drive. RAM is
        usually bought in quantities of gigabytes(GB) in increments of 8 GBs in single stick or multiple
        all the way up to 128 GBs of RAM.
    </string>
    <string name="stor_desc">
        Storage is a very important component of the PC just like everything else in the PC. The storage component
        is a piece of hardware that has the capability to hold information within a certain time frame or forever.
        In other words, it is a place to store your data either temporarily or permanently.
    </string>
    <string name="psu_desc">
        Gives power to all the components in the PC.
    </string>
    <string name="cpucool_desc">
        The CPU cooler job to make sure the CPU has the proper cooling it needs. By keeping the CPU
        cool, the computer is able to run more efficiently. The CPU could reach unsafe temperatures
        which could damage it. There are two main ways to cool a CPU.
    </string>
    <string name="case_desc">
        The case houses all the computer’s components. It protects everything inside and influences
        the airflow in the case. There are four main types when choosing a computer case. When choosing
        the right case it’s important to check the components that may have trouble fitting in the case.
        The motherboard, the length of the GPU, air CPU cooler height, and liquid cooling radiator size
        are some common compatibility issues. The last two factors when choosing the right case is the
        aesthetics and the cooling possibilities it provides. The aesthetics are composed of the outside
        like color, but also the kind of cable management options it offers. The cooling possibilities
        are important since more areas for fans or better airflow will make for cooler components that
        will last you longer.
    </string>
    <string name="os_desc">
        An operating system is installed on the computer’s hard drive which allows the user to operate
        other software. It manages all peripherals connected as well as the hardware connected. There are
        a lot of operating systems and branches of them, but here will discuss the main three options for
        desktop computers.
    </string>
    <string name="mon_desc">
        The monitor is the display of the system. It will display any and everything you want to do with
        the computer. It is important to figure out what you will be using the system for to then decide
        which size, resolution, and refresh rate.
    </string>
    <string name="per_desc">
        The peripherals are the many accessories that one can plug into a computer. It will add functionality
        and need a computer to function. They commonly connect using USB, but may use different ports or more
        than one.
    </string>

    <!--Ports Description-->
    <string name="gpu_ports_description">
        Depending on the GPU you purchase and when you purchased it the ports on the GPU may differ
        a little, but not by too much. For example, if you were to purchase a GPU back in 2003 the
        ports that would be included with it would consist of the DVI port, a VGA port and a S-Video
        port. If you were to purchase the up and coming GPU in the market you would find yourself having
        many HDMI ports, some DisplayPorts and depending on the GPU manufacturer you could find yourself
        having a DVI or even a VGA port.
    </string>
    <string name="cpu_ports_description">
        The main two companies producing CPUs are AMD and Intel. The core count can go from two all the
        way up to sixty-four for professional settings. Clock speed is another piece of information that
        is advertised a lot when shopping for CPUs. Clock speed is measured in megahertz(MHz) or gigahertz
        (GHz) and means how many instructions a CPU can handle per second. The speed of the computer will
        depend on multiple factors other than the clock speed like the other components.
    </string>
    <string name="mem_ports_description">
    </string>
    <string name="stor_ports_description">
        When you store information for a short amount of time the PC will normally store it in the RAM(Memory),
        if you would like to learn more about the Memory component please click on the Memory page. The second
        place in which information is stored is the HDD(Hard Drive Disk) or SSD(Solid State Drive). These
        components are the
    </string>
    <string name="mot_ports_description">
        The back panel of the motherboard holds many of the ports needed to attach peripherals to interact
        with the computer. Most newer boards contain a HDMI or Displayport for the monitor, usb ports for
        mouse and keyboard or any more accessories, and many I/O connectors.
    </string>
    <string name="psu_ports_description">
        Connection for the power cord to the computer, the fan that pulls out the heat from the internal
        of the PSU, a switch to change the voltage provided and a rocker switch to turn the power supply
        on and off.
    </string>
    <string name="cpucool_ports_description">
        The typical method of cooling is a heat sink or heat sink with a fan. The cooler is
        placed with a pea sized drop of thermal paste to help cool it. The heat is moved away from
        the CPU and the fan can push it out. Additional case fans can help with the general air flow
        in the computer. This cooling type is typically inexpensive and even is included with some
        CPUs.
        Another method of cooling is liquid cooling. It is a more advanced, more expensive type of
        cooling that generally makes the CPU cooler than it would be with the heat sink combo. It is not
        recommended for CPUs that are not prone to overheating because the first heating type would
        be enough. Liquid cooling is more quiet than the fan method with the potential to cool other
        parts of the system like the GPU. Overall, the system will end up quieter, but any potential
        mistake may be expensive.
    </string>
    <string name="case_ports_description">
        Full Tower is the large case.
	    Mid Tower is the medium size of the case.
	    Micro-ATX is the small.
	    Mini-ITX is the smallest size.
        Overall all these cases need to be checked against the motherboard the customer is picking
        since different cases have different dimensions. Finding the right motherboard for your case
        should not be difficult with the case spec sheet listing what motherboard sizes it will be
        compatible with. This is also true for the other three parts listed above where it is important
        to check specs of the component and the case to see if they will fit the case.
    </string>
    <string name="os_ports_description">
        Windows is the most common operating system with many versions with the latest being Windows 11
        recently. Windows being the most popular also comes with many types of viruses and malware
        targeting it, but with smart internet uses users do not need to worry. It is favored among gamers
        because most if not all games made for PC will run on windows.This goes for many other pieces of
        software because it’s popularity, most companies will make sure it is able to run on windows first.
        MacOS is another popular operating system used on Apple laptops and desktops. Outside of the Apple
        ecosystem of products it is less commonly seen because it requires more knowledge and work to get a
        working “Hackintosh”. MacOS was made for only Apple products so building a computer and trying to
        use this operating system will take work. If you get an Apple product or “Hackintosh” then you will
        notice a smaller selection of software options. An Apple laptop is also limited in upgradeability a
        lot of work which will void warranties. Being less popular means that less viruses are made for it
        which makes it safer. Many games can be played on MacOS, but the options will be limited and may
        vary in run quality because of the dependence on the laptop specs.Linux is a free and open source
        operating system. The open source allows many distributions to be available with specialized functions
        such as servers. It also allows users to escape the corporate operating systems to a more open source
        environment. It can be customized to one’s desire.The amount of customizability can be intimidating
        leaving users unfamiliar with command line confused. Gaming will be very limited on it and same for
        software. If learned, one could take advantage of its full potential.
    </string>
    <string name="mon_ports_description">
        Size is just the screen size. It is labeled in inches and it is listed as the diagonal length when
        purchasing a monitor. Which you pick will depend on how big of a screen you like.Resolution is
        the number of pixels that make up a screen. The more pixels means the higher resolution which makes
        for a sharper image. The more common resolution you will see is Full HD (FHD) which is 1920x1080,
        but it can go as high as 5k which is 5120 x 2880. It is important to make sure your system can
        handle a 4k monitor before purchasing one.Refresh rate is a feature that only really matters to
        gamers. It is measured in hertz(Hz) and is the number of times the monitor updates with new
        information per second. The high refresh rate then the less choppy an image. It can matter for
        high paced gameplay, but for office or home use then any monitor should work fine.
    </string>
    <string name="per_ports_description">
        Mouse helps in controlling the computer by clicking where a user decides they want to go.Keyboard
        is also important because it allows for more interactions on a computer. Typing allows users to search
        and make documents.Speakers are often an accessory because most monitors do not come with built in
        speakers. It allows the users to listen to music and video over their system.Printer is the last
        common peripheral you will find. It allows you to print out documents and any other pages one chooses.
    </string>

    <string-array name="comp_names">
        <item>CPU</item>
        <item>MotherBoard</item>
        <item>Memory</item>
        <item>Storage</item>
        <item>Power Supply</item>
        <item>CPU Cooler</item>
        <item>Monitor</item>
        <item>Video Card</item>
        <item>Case</item>
        <item>Raspberry Pi</item>
        <item>Arduino</item>
        <item>OS</item>
        <item>Peripherals</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_login">LoginActivity</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome !"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_login">real_login</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="hello_first_fragment">Hello first fragment</string>
    <string name="hello_second_fragment">Hello second fragment. Arg: %1$s</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_register">real_register</string>
    <string name="title_activity_real_profile">real_profile</string>
    <string name="title_activity_education_tabbed">Education_Tabbed</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Beginner</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Moderate</string>
    <string name="tab_text_3">Expert</string>

    <string name="link_title">Links to Further your knowledge</string>
    <string name="cpu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mot_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/m/mothboar.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/m/mothboar.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mem_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/r/ram.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/r/ram.htm</a></string>
    <string name="stor_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/s/stordevi.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/s/stordevi.htm</a></string>
    <string name="gpu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/v/video-card.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/v/video-card.htm</a></string>
    <string name="psu_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/p/power-supply.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/p/power-supply.htm</a></string>
    <string name="cpucool_link"><a href="https://www.newegg.com/insider/how-to-choose-the-right-cpu-cooler-pc-radiator-for-you/">newegg.com/insider/how-to-choose-the-right-cpu-cooler-pc-radiator-for-you/</a></string>
    <string name="case_link"><a href="https://techguided.com/how-to-choose-a-pc-case/">techguided.com/how-to-choose-a-pc-case/</a></string>
    <string name="os_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mon_link"><a href="https://www.newegg.com/insider/how-to-choose-the-best-computer-monitor-buying-guide/">newegg.com/insider/how-to-choose-the-best-computer-monitor-buying-guide/</a></string>
    <string name="per_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/p/peripher.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/p/peripher.htm</a></string>
    <string name="button">Button</string>
    <!--
    <string name="rasp_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="ard_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="cool_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="case_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="os_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="mon_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    <string name="per_link"><a href="https://www.computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm">computerhope.com/jargon/c/cpu.htm</a></string>
    -->
    <string name="pref_previously_started">false</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pc_part">PC_Part_Activity</string>



    <string name="navigation_draw_open">open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_draw_close">close navigation drawer</string>
    <string-array name="quiz">
        <item>Building</item>
        <item>Social</item>
        <item>Education</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>